>> Hi and welcome to section two on text processing.
This is where we look at some of
the tasks and techniques involved in acquiring data,
cleaning it and normalizing it.
So, the first section here,
the task is data acquisition.
And some of the issues involved in data acquisition are,
where do I get the data that I need?
And, is it already in
digital form or does it need to be OCRed?
How much will it cost or is it free?
Is this the only delivery of
the data I need or will I need updates over time?
And, if it's customer data,
do I have the legal and privacy rights
needed to use the data in the way I intend to use it?
And, if the data needs to be safeguard,
do I have the systems
in place to securely store the data?
So, one alternative that's
used for some applications is to
use existing collections of
data from various repositories on the web.
In nltk, we have access to lots of different resources.
What I'm going to look at here are the Gutenberg books.
So, here we have import nltk and
then I'm going to print out
the corpus Gutenberg file ids.
This will just show me the names of
the books that are available.
I'll execute the cell and I
get back austen- emma, austen-persuasion.
You can see, I think there's something
like a 15 or something.
So let's look at one of the books.
Let's look at Alice in Wonderland.
So, to do that I just say gutenberg.words and
then the name of the book and store that in Alice,
and then I can see how large it is by length of Alice and
I'll print out the first 100 entries.
So there we see it's 34,000
words long and you
can see some of the beginning words here,
Rabbit, Hole, Alice was beginning to get very tired.
So that looks like that worked.
Let's try another one.
This one is from the webtext.words and it's grail.text.
So, this a Monty Python and the Holy Grail script.
And so, we can see here-,
the other one Arthur I
am this is my trusty servant Patsy.
Okay, so it looks like that worked.